好极了
Oh, good job.
今天真是个好天气
Oh, yes, such a beautiful day.
我们找一个阳光猛烈的地方吃早午餐吧
Let's go have brunch somewhere outside
好让我显摆一下我的新眼镜
Where I can wear my new sunglasses, huh?
天啊 你怎么了
Ew, gross! What happened to you?
我身体不适
I don't feel good.
我忽热
I'm hot.
忽冷
Now I'm cold.
不会吧
Oh, no.
可我们今晚还要去看演唱会
and we have that concert tonight.
我知道 亲爱的
I know, but, honey,
现在先别担心这个 身体要紧
That's the furthest thing from my mind, okay?
为什么是我
Why me?!
我们买了女神卡卡演唱会里最棒的位置
We had amazing seats for Lady GAGA,
可他却病了
and he gets sick.
我期待那场演唱会好几个月了
I'd been looking forward to that concert for months.
这是我允许自己表现得像个同志的唯一一点
It's the one gay cliche I allow myself.
别吵了
No more fighting!
求求你们别再吵了
No more fighting for the rest of your lives,
你们不许这样互吼
You are not allowed to yell at each other.
-那你怎么就可以吼我们呢 -对 艾丽克斯 我可以
- But you're allowed to yell at us? - Yes, alex, I am,
那是因为我给你做饭 给你们买衣服
Because I feed you and I clothe you
连你们住的房子也是我来还房贷
And I pay the mortgage.
看来你们老爹也机会一展狮吼绝技啊
Pretty sure old dad deserves a shout-out right about now.
-菲尔 -抱歉
- Phil! - Sorry.
没想到战况这么激烈
Should've taken the temperature of the room first.
怎么了
What's up?
卢克和曼尼 这两个小变态
Luke and Manny barged into our room
在我们更衣时闯进我们的房间
While we were changing, the little pervs!
我能插句话吗 在欧洲这可不算什么
Can I just say, in europe this would be no big deal.
没错 你们可以随时看我穿内裤的样子
Yeah. You can see me in my underwear whenever you want.
来 现在就给你们看
Here, I'll make it even.
-卢克 别这样 -老妈 你看他
- No, hey, Luke, Luke, Luke! - Mom!
卢克 别脱裤子
Luke, keep your pants on, okay?!
女儿们 别什么事都这么歇斯底里
And, girls, stop getting so hysterical over everything!
拜托 成熟点行不行
Come on! Now, grow up a little!
我需要这里的风气稍微改改
I need things to start changing around here,
不然我会强制你们改
Or I will change things, okay?
禁止看电视 禁止上网
There will be no more TV and no internet
还有禁止其他我能想到的事
And no whatever else I can think of.
我能和你说几句吗 菲尔
May I have a word with you, Phil?
能不说最好
I'd rather not.
刚那算什么
What was that?
-没什么 -你在我背后捅我一刀 菲尔
- Nothing. - Phil, you sold me out behind my back.
哪有 只是觉得你有时太过严厉
No! It's just that sometimes you can get a little intense,
我觉得我有必要小闹一下
And I feel like I need to swoop in
让孩子们知道我们还是爱他们的
To let the kids know they're still loved.
一脚踢飞你
I could kick you.
亲爱的 为人父母都这样
Honey, these are just the parts that we're playing.
我错了吗 这招能管用吗
Am I wrong, or has it been working?
我感觉挺管用的
I feel like it's been working.
我受够了总是当坏人
I'm tired of being the bad cop.
有时需要你出面来管教下他们
You need to discipline them sometime
等我这个好人来让他们感受被爱
And let me swoop in with all the love.
难道咱们不应该坚守在自己擅长的岗位上吗
Shouldn't we just stick with the stuff we're good at?
天啊 这卫生间太恶心了
Oh, my god! This bathroom is disgusting!
女孩们几天前就答应我说会打扫的
The girls told me they would clean it days ago.
我不能再对她们大吼大叫了 菲尔
I can't yell at them about it one more time, Phil.
该你上了
You handle it.
我也想 可我答应卢克和曼尼
I would, but I promised Luke and Manny
要带他们去玩卡丁车 以此奖励他们的成绩
I'd take them go-karting for their good report cards.
卢克的成绩哪里好了
What was good about Luke's report card?
反正没有不及格
He didn't lose it.
我带他们去
Let me take them.
没错 让我去吧 你呆在家
Yes, let me take them. You stay here.
敦促女孩们打扫卫生
Hound the girls about cleaning up this mess,
而我会带卢克好好玩的
And I will take Luke to do something fun.
可
But...
我想玩卡丁车
I want to go go-karting.
真可惜 我不知道该对你说什么
Yeah, I don't know what to tell you.
可木已成舟
This is happening.
男孩们
Boys!
孩子们 猜猜谁今天带你们玩卡丁车
Hey, guys, guess who's taking you go-karting today.
我
Me.
为什么
Why?
我们闯祸了吗
Are we in trouble?
哪有 你们没有闯祸
No! You're not in trouble.
今天我要带你们玩个够
Today's just all about having fun!
告诉你们 卡丁车只是个开头
And you know what? Go-karting's just the beginning.
我们还能玩什么
What else are we doing?
玩什么都行
Whatever you want.
-我想带上老爸 -估计悬 不能带
- I want to bring dad. - Well, tough. You can't.
他有事要做
He's doing something else.
各位再见 我们几个小时后回来
Goodbye. We will be back in a few hours.
等等 你们要去哪
Oh, whoa! Where you guys going?
我要带艾丽克斯去看电影
I am taking Alex to the movies,
然后我再去趟购物中心
And then I'm going to the mall.
听起来很有趣 是不 菲尔
How fun! That sounds like fun, doesn't it, Phil?
我又不是个购物狂 可这取决于
I'm not much of a shopper, but it would depend on --
打扫洗手间
Clean bathroom.
女儿们
Girls...
你们出门之前先打扫一下洗手间吧
How about you clean your bathroom before you go, huh?
算帮你们老妈点忙
It'd really help your mom out.
不用 我可没提这种要求
Oh, no. It's not about what mom wants.
你们老妈无所谓
You mom is cool,
对任何事都无所谓
Very cool with whatever.
提这种要求的可是你们老爸
It's about what dad wants.
老爸想去玩卡丁车
Dad wants to go go-karting.
我非常希望你们能去打扫一下洗手间
I would really like it if you would clean your bathroom.
那我的电影怎么办
But my movie!
为什么非要现在做
Why do we have to do it now?
因为克莱尔说了
Because Claire says so.
因为我说了
Because I say so.
还因为我是你们老爸
And because I'm your dad.
我比你们年长
And I'm older than you,
这儿我说了算
and I call the shots around here.
-是吗 -对 是的
- Right? - Yes, you do.
这太不公平了
This is so unfair!
走吧 儿子 我们去玩玩
Come on, guys, let's go have some fun!
-你把我拉疼了 -你没事的
- Ow! You're hurting me. - Oh, you're fine!
玩的开心点 孩子们
Have fun, guys.
走 走 走
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
那
So...
应该先从什么开始
How does this usually start?
普里契特先生 早上好
Good morning, Mr. Pritchett.
你好 你是斯波特吧
How you doing, Sport?
我不知道那是谁 从来都不知道
I didn't know who that was. I never do.
至少每月会有一天
At least once a month,
我家厨房里会坐着一位陌生人
I find a total stranger sitting in my kitchen.
歌洛莉亚收留各种流浪汉
Gloria collects every kind of stray
求职的求财的 应有尽有
looking for work, money, you name it.
她有一颗仁善之心
She's got a big heart.
这是唯一我希望改变她的地方
It's the one thing I'd like to change about her.
哇 狗狗 这个少见
Hey, a dog. That's new.
那就是普里契特先生
That was Mr. Pritchett.
杰 你来啦 过来
Oh, Jay, there you are. Come.
我给你介绍一下吉尔莫
I want to introduce you to Guillermo.
刚见过了 很谈得来
Just met him. Really hit it off.
亲爱的 预算控制在100美元之内
Honey, keep it under a hundred bucks,
根本连说都不必跟我说
you don't even have to tell me.
-我要去打高尔夫了 -不行 等等
- I'm going golfing. - No.
他人很好 在杂货店工作
He's a very nice man that works at the grocery store
需要一些业务咨询
and needs a little bit of business advice.
怎么早不说呢
Oh, why didn't you say so?
我还以为他是住在
I thought he was just some nut
干洗店的无赖呢
who lived behind the dry cleaner's.
我们上个月帮他矫正鞋那家伙才是
Oh, that's the guy we bought corrective shoes for last month.
杰 他知道你很成功
Jay, he knows how successful you are,
他只是需要你给一小时 或半小时
And all he wants is an hour of your t-- half-hour.
十分钟 我跟他保证过
10 minutes. I promise him!
亲爱的 我爱你
Honey, I love you,
但是你为什么拉我搀和进去呢
but why do you drag me into these things?
你要学会拒绝别人
You've got to learn to say no to people.
好 那你先问问我让不让你去打高尔夫
Fine. Ask me if you can go golfing now.
是拒绝其他人
Other people.
我想要的不过是 晚上睡觉时
All I want is, when I go to bed at night,
身边躺着的是一个慷慨而乐施的男人
to be laying next to a man that is generous and giving.
看来我要换个人躺了
And that man doesn't necessarily need to be you.
行 那我们过去吧
Okay, let's do this.
好的 吉尔莫
Okay. Guillermo!
需要我把废纸篓放近一点吗
Do you want me to move the waste basket closer to you?
-不用了 在哪儿都一样 -是吗
- Oh, no. It's fine where it is. - Really?
但床看上去像花车游行的彩车
'cause the bed kind of looks like a rose parade float.
谢谢你照顾我
Thank you for taking care of me.
这是应该的
Well, what else would I be doing?
当然还应该去看女神卡卡
Um, seeing lady gaga, that's what.
小卡 我也不想现在就提这茬
So, uh, Cam, you know, I hate to bring this up,
但是那演唱会怎么办
but what are we gonna do about that concert?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你知道的 我们都想去看
Well, you know, we were both looking forward to going.
你想去看
You were looking forward to going.
我是真的很想去看
I was really looking forward to going.
而且 我不想眼睁睁看着门票浪费了
And I just -- I-I hate to see those tickets go to waste.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
那我们还有什么办法吗
But what are our options?
我们可以一起去看演唱会
We could both go to the concert.
还是算了吧
That's not gonna happen.
我们可以到网上把票卖掉
Uh, well, we could sell the tickets online.
不过一转手到网上就掉价了
But there's that craigslist killer.
咋办呢 咋办呢
Oh, what to do? What to do?
What to do? What to do? What to do?
想办法 想办法
Other options, other options.
米奇尔 你是在暗示
Mitchell, are you hinting
你要丢下我独自去看演唱会
that you want to go to that concert without me?
不 不 绝不可能
No! No! Not in a million years!
但我很欣慰你主动提议
But that's very sweet of you to offer.
-我没提议任何事 -真的吗
- I didn't offer.- Oh, really?
感觉你就应该会说
'cause that just seems like something that you would say
你去吧 我没事
"You go, I'll be fine.
你为了买票倾尽所有
You spent all the money on the tickets,
我会乖乖躺在床上等你回来的
And I'm just gonna lie in bed anyways."
这才是小卡的作风
That's classic Cam.
-我太虚弱了 -好吧 行
- I'm just so weak. - Okay, good.
那就这样吧
You know what? It's settled.
咱们就忘掉
We're just gonna put this whole
"你坚持要我自己去看演唱会"
"You insisting I go to the concert without you"
这回事吧
thing behind us.
其实呢
You know what?
其实什么
What?
我能吃一小杯布丁吗
Can I get one of my little pudding cups?
可以 当然可以拉
Yes, you can. Yes.
你是欢乐地吃布丁
You eat the pudding,
哥是含泪要吞票
and I'll eat the tickets.
多谢您的款待 普里契特先生
Thanks for your dining, Mr.Pritchett.
但等会你听过我的报告之后
But after you hearing my presentation,
你就会反过来谢我了
you will be thanking me.
你倒是很自信 这点我很欣赏
Well, you've got confidence. I admire that.
他看好你哦 吉尔莫
He admires that, Guillermo.
表现不错 再接再厉
You're doing great. Keep going.
你是否知道 仅去年一年
Are you aware that last year,
美国人就在驯犬上花费了四百亿美元
Americans spent $40 billion on dog training?
压根没这回事
Well, that's not true.
我和你一样 对此大跌眼镜
I was surprised as you are.
你跌眼镜是因为压根没这回事
No, you were surprised because it's not true.
嘘 接着说 吉尔莫
Shh! Go on, Guillermo.
这个价值数十亿的产业 究竟缺失了什么呢
What is this multibillion-dollar industry missing?
好一个"数十亿"
Multibillion dollars.
我提出了一个革命性的人犬交互方案...
I have devised a revolutionary way to communicate --
听着 我无意打断你的长篇大论
Listen, I hate to interrupt your big pitch,
但是你的狗狗在啃我家抱枕
but your dog is chewing my pillow.
太妙了
This is fantastic.
对我家枕头来说 一点也不妙
It's not fantastic for my pillow.
这是个供我展示"好狗狗坏狗狗"
It's a perfect opportunity for me to demonstrate
驯犬系统的绝妙机会
the good doggie bad doggie training system.
-我们一定入股 -等下 慢着
- We're in! - Wait, slow down.
枕头的问题你打算怎么解决
What are we gonna do about the pillow situation?
现在就是见证奇迹的时刻
Watch, and be amazed.
斯黛拉现在不乖
Stella here is being a bad doggie.
斯黛拉 松口 坏狗狗 坏狗狗
Stella, let go. Bad dog, bad dog.
坏狗狗 坏狗狗会得到什么呢
Bad dog. And what does a bad dog get?
一块坏狗狗奖励
A bad-doggie treat.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你是奖励她干坏事吗
You give her a treat for doing something bad?
这是坏狗狗奖励
Ah, a bad-doggie treat.
等她乖了 就能得到好狗狗奖励
When she is good, she gets the good-doggie treat.
天才啊 我们要发啦
Brilliant! We're going to be rich!
慢着慢着慢着
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
这个坏狗狗好狗狗的奖励
What is the difference between a bad-doggie treat
究竟有什么区别
and the good-doggie treat?
都是培根 但坏狗狗奖励淡而无味
Bacon. The bad-doggie treat is very bland.
我看她好像挺喜欢吃的
But she seems like she likes it.
等看完好狗狗奖励再说吧
Wait till you see the good-doggie treat.
斯黛拉 坐下
Stella, sit.
现在是好狗狗奖励
Now a good-doggie treat.
好吧 刚才坏狗狗奖励吃撑了
Okay, uh, she's still full from the bad-doggie treat.
不过这就是
But there you have it --
好狗狗坏狗狗驯犬系统
the good doggie bad doggie training system.
欢迎来到发财之路的开端
Welcome to the ground floor.
其实 你的狗正在我家地板尿尿呢
Actually, she's peeing on the ground floor.
快点 快给她一块坏狗狗奖励
Quick, quick, give her a bad-doggie treat!
喂
Hello?
喂 是我 不方便接电话吗
Hey, it's me. Is this a bad time?
没有 我在车里呢
No, I'm just in the car.
好吧 我陷入了良知的挣扎
Okay, I'm having a moral dilemma.
我们买了女神卡卡今晚演唱会的票 但是小卡病了
We have tickets for lady gaga tonight, but Cam's sick.
那我去
I'll take them.
但你根本不喜欢演唱会
Wait, you don't even like concerts.
我喜欢 我现在是享乐派
Yes, I do. I'm fun now.
克莱尔 他们说要满十三岁
Claire, they said we have to be at least 13
才能开快车
to ride the fast ones.
他们满十三了 没事的
They're 13. It's fine.
这可把我整糊涂了
This is very confusing.
上次去电影院时 她说我十一岁
At movie theaters, she says I'm 11.
-咱能接着谈我的事吗 -什么
- Can we get back to me? - What?
如果抛下他去看演唱会
Does it make me a horrible person
我会不会显得很没人性啊
that I kind of want to go without him?
他病得有多厉害
Well, how sick is he?
不好说 就是病了
I don't know. He's sick.
没到要帮他做回忆录的程度
You know, they're not gonna make a lifetime movie about him.
那你生病的时候 他表现得怎样
Well, what's he like when you're sick?
小卡 我自己能走到厨房
Cam, I think I can walk to the kitchen.
表现还不错
He's okay.
那你就去吧
You should go.
知道我今天学到些什么吗
You know what I learned today?
想要什么
You can't wait around
不能干等着别人给你
for somebody to give you something you want.
有时你要自己去争取
Sometimes you just have to take it.
但我会很过意不去的
Oh, I'm gonna feel so guilty, though.
如果你留下了 你会怨他的
You'll resent him if you stay.
那这样好了 你呆在家
So, how about this -- you stay home
照顾他 喂他喝汤 帮他足底按摩
and take care of him -- soup, foot rubs,
-帮他擦鼻子 -好恶心
- you blow his nose. - Ew.
有夫如此 他真是走运
He's so lucky to have you.
就今晚在音乐会开始之前 你对他说
And then tonight, right before the concert, you say,
"小卡 我爱你 但我真的很想去"
"Cam, I love you, but I really want to go."
他会同意的
He'll say fine.
你去时顺便把莉莉放我家 皆大欢喜
You drop Lily off at our house, and it's great.
车手 启动引擎
Drivers, start your engines.
我把扬声器打开
I'm putting you on speaker.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
让我的孩子们爱上我
Making my kids love me!
车手 准备 三 二 一
Drivers, ready. Three, two, one!
你出局啦 迪尔加多
You're going down, Delgado!
尝尝这个
Like this!
我们把厕所清理干净了
We're finished cleaning the bathroom.
我们走啦
We're leaving.
看吧 不会占用你们多长时间
See? That didn't take too long.
谢谢 姑娘们
Thank you, girls.
现在出去 好好玩 知道吗
Now, go and have a good time, all right?
再见
Bye.
看吧 你不需跟她们起冲突
See? You don't need all the conflict.
提醒克莱尔 如果你想看激烈的家庭戏
Note to Claire -- if you want intense family drama,
租部《非常小特务》
rent "Spy kids."
他们挽救了父母的生命
They save their parents' lives.
如果他们整天被父母嚷嚷
You think they would've done that
你觉得他们还会这么做吗
if they got yelled at all the time?
这俩小妞玩阴的
Sweet and sour chicken!
姑娘们
Girls!
回来 得把这楼梯修好
Get back h-- got to fix that step.
姑娘们
Girls!
他刚嚷咱们了
Did he just yell?
-快开车 -我在开呢
- Drive! - I'm trying!
你们给我马上回来
You girls get back here right now!
假装你什么都没听到
Pretend you don't hear him.
我知道你们听到了
I know you can hear me!
天 他直接朝车奔来了
Oh, my god, he's heading straight for the car!
天
Oh, my god! Aah!
停车
Stop this car!
-对不起 爸爸 -我们没听到
- We're sorry, dad! - We couldn't hear you!
不许再撒谎
No more lies!
姑娘们 你们惹到我了
You poked the bear, girls!
这是你们自找的
You poked him!
最后 真正的问题是
In closing, the only real question is,
在你投资了好狗狗坏狗狗后
after you invest in good doggie bad doggie,
我们怎么才能把所有的钱花完呢
How will we spend all our money?
买手提包
In handbags!
不 还是度假好
No, vacation!
我知道了 家庭健身房
I know! A home gym!
好的 吉列莫 你的野心具有传染性
All right, Guillermo, your ambition is infectious.
显然我妻子需要接种疫苗
Clearly my wife needs to be inoculated.
但我还是得坦率的说
But I'm gonna be blunt.
-不不 你不会是要 -是的 没错
- Ay, no, no, you're not going to - Yes, I am.
你想要听到诚实的商业建议 对吗
Now, you wanted my honest business advice, right?
-非常想 -那你听着
- Very much. - Here it is.
你的主意不咋的
Your idea is not good.
不 杰是说
No, what Jay means is that when --
不 我是说这主意太烂了
No, what I mean is it stinks.
我不是针对你这个人
Now, that's nothing against you.
你很帅气
You've got charm,
你有野心 这很棒
you've got ambition, and that's great.
你需要的只是一个更好主意
What you need is a better idea.
但我没有更好的主意
But I don't have a better idea.
任何想法都将会是个好主意
Any idea would be a better idea.
你的话真如醍醐灌耳
Your honesty is refreshing.
谢谢
Gracias.
你把他弄哭了
Ay, you made him cry.
他没哭
He's not crying.
你不是在哭 是吧
You're not crying, are you?
没
No.
小泣而已
A little.
我花费了五年 却一事无成
It's just five years of my life are for nothing.
五 五年
Five? Five years?
吉列莫 对不起
Ay, Guillermo, I'm sorry.
不如你在这吃个中饭吧
Why don't you stay for lunch?
我们可以为你的下个主意出谋划策
And -- and we can all brainstorm your next idea.
真的吗 谢谢你 歌洛莉亚
Really? Thank you, Gloria.
我去把斯黛拉放进车里
I go put Stella in the car.
我不想她再破坏你家精美的东西
I don't want her ruining any more of your beautiful things.
谢谢
Gracias.
坏狗狗
Bad dog.
你为什么要对他这么严厉
Why were you so tough with him?
他很敏感的
He's very sensitive.
你认为那是个好主意吗
Did you think that was a good idea?
当然不是
Of course not!
但是我是个好人 我会婉转地说
But I'm nice, and I put on the sugar jacket.
婉转是帮不了他的
Sugar coating is not gonna help him.
他需要听进去我对他说的
He needed to hear what I said to him,
即使这话小小的刺伤了他
Even if it hurt a little bit.
总有一天他会感谢我的
He's gonna thank me one day.
吉列莫 现在我要道歉了
Ay! Guillermo! Now I have to apologize.
我原谅你
Accepted.
不是对你
Not to you!
你想要什么 卢克
What are you gonna get, Luke?
-我想要起司汉堡 -好的
- I want a cheeseburger. - Yeah!
法式薯条和洋葱圈我不知道选哪个
And I can't decide between french fries or onion rings.
那就都要了
Get them both!
你呢 曼尼
How about you, Manny?
你们有去皮的烤鸡胸肉吗
Um, do you have a skinless grilled chicken breast?
不是吧 你是要参加舞会吗 灰姑娘
What, are you going to the ball, cinderella?
我知道克莱尔在逗趣
I know Claire was trying to be fun,
但那太过分了
but that crossed the line.
还要别的吗 要奶昔吗
Anything else? Who wants a milkshake?
要吗 要吗 来三份奶昔
Milkshake? Milkshake? Three milkshakes.
我不想要奶昔
I didn't really want a milkshake.
但听了她对曼尼说的话后
But after what she said to Manny,
我决定明哲保身
I didn't want to risk it.
妈妈 我不舒服
Mom, I don't feel good.
你的奶昔喝完了吗
Did you finish your milkshake?
我觉得就是奶昔害的
I think that was the problem.
你以为你是医生啊
Look who's a doctor now.
可能是派有问题
Maybe it was the pie.
他没事的
Oh, he's fine. Hey.
你们要玩过山车吗
Hey, who likes roller coasters?
我需要一个袋子
I need a bag.
卢克 你不会有事的
No. No, you're not gonna be sick, Luke.
我们玩得正欢呢
We're having fun.
好吧
Okay.
不 我真得需要一个袋子
No, I really need a bag.
把杯子的盖拿掉
Take the lid off the cup.
我饿死了
I'm starving.
我也一样 说些什么吧
Me too. Say something.
爸爸 我们午饭还没吃呢
Um, dad? We haven't had lunch yet.
非洲的孩子也没东西吃
Neither have half the kids in Africa.
不要废话 继续干活
Stop yapping and get back to work.
他干嘛把我们的笔记本用胶带封上
Why is he taping our laptops shut?
因为他疯了
Because he's out of his mind.
我没疯
I'm not out of my mind!
你们耍赖那刻起 就失去了用电脑的权利
You took advantage,and you lost your computer privileges.
爸爸 拜托 我们知道错了
Oh, come on, dad. We said we're sorry.
而且我真不会疏通下水道
Plus I can't get the stupid drain unclogged, anyway.
用挂钩伸下去
Stick that hanger down there.
不
Ew, no!
要么疏通下水道 要么你们剃光头
Well, it's either that or we cut off all your hair,
因为你们的头发是元凶 怎么样啊
'cause that's what caused the problem -- thoughts?
很好 清理完这个房间后
Good, because after you finish this room,
你们去清理我的卫生间
you're gonna clean my bathroom, too,
你们还可以知道我有多恶心
and you know how gross I can be.
爸爸 不
Dad! No!
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, my gosh!
-真恶心 -好了
- Ew! Gross! - All right.
淡定 头发而已
Aah! Settle down. It's hair.
天啊
Oh, my god.
我不适合做这些
I'm not cut out for this.
我一整天都在照顾小卡
I spent all day nursing Cam.
可以换右脚了吗
Ohh. Hey, could you do the right one now?
是一开始就按过的那只吗 当然可以
You mean the one we started with? Sure.
我煮汤泡茶 做牛做马
I made soup. I made tea.
终于 到了说真心话的关键时刻了
Finally, it was the moment of truth.
小卡 我想
Cam, you know, I was thinking that...
小卡 你可以不同意
Cam, you can say no,
但我想去演唱会
but I was thinking about maybe going to that concert.
谢谢 你最好了 我爱你
Thank you. You're the best. I love you.
你回来了 你的朋友呢
Hey, you're back. What happened with your friend?
他还好 你是对的
He's fine. You were right.
他很欣赏你的真诚
He did appreciate your honesty.
然后怎么样
How about that?
他要改变他的生活
He's gonna make big changes to his life.
很好
Good.
他要回去上学
He's going back to school.
那就意味着 他要和他姐一起住
That means he has to go back to live with his sister,
那也意味着 他不能养狗
so that means that he had to get rid of the dog.
他现在现实多了
But he's so much more realistic now.
看到了吧
See that? Mm.
顺便也给你上了一课
And there's a lesson in there for you, too,
有时候拒绝会让事情会变得更好
'cause sometimes things go better when you just say no.
不 你做了什么
No, no, no. What did you do?
他要把它送到动物收留所
Ay! He was going to take her to the pound.
那是他的事
But that's his business.
-看看它的小脸 -不
- Ay, but look at her little face! - No.
你根本不想要狗
You don't even want a dog.
我知道 我在这方面有问题
I know. I have a problem.
见鬼 曼尼回来了
Oh, crap, that's Manny.
他如果看见这只狗 就完了
If he sees the dog, it's all over.
我去锁门
I go lock the door.
那可以解决问题吗
Oh, and that's the solution?
在这狗老死之前 曼尼都在后院睡吗
Manny sleeps in the backyard till the dog dies of old age?
我回来了
Hey, guys. I'm home.
我觉得克莱尔遇到了一些事情
Boy, I think Claire's working through some stuff, because --
天啊
Oh, my gosh!
你们因为我的成绩 奖励我一只狗吗
You got me a dog because of my perfect report card?
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?
对不起 亲爱的 不是
Sorry, papi, no.
这只狗要呆在另外一个地方
The dog lives somewhere else,
现在就要送它过去
which is where she's going right now.
-把地址发给我 -好吧
- Text me the address. - Okay.
可以给我一点时间 跟她告别吗
Can I at least take a moment with her to tell her goodbye?
跟她告别 你才见到她
Tell her goodbye? You just met her.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
卢克 宝贝 回来 对不起
Luke, honey, come back. I said I was sorry.
我才十二岁 我需要被人管
I'm 12. I need limits!
发生什么事了
What happened?
我让他们把卡丁车开得太快了
Oh, I made them drive too fast
还让他们吃得跟维京人[海盗]那么多
and eat like vikings,
结果卢克吐得满车都是
and then Luke threw up all over the car.
我得去清理一下
I got to go clean that up.
不 不用你清 姑娘们
No, you don't. Girls!
拿上你们的水桶 咱们车子那儿见
Grab your buckets and meet me by the car!
不用她们干
They don't have to do that.
我说了她们就得干
They do if I say so.
真抱歉
I'm sorry.
我刚说了拿上你们的水桶
I swear I just told you to grab your buckets!
我们一整天都没吃东西了
We haven't eaten all day.
我们饿了
We're hungry.
你们马上就不饿了
Well, you won't be in a minute.
亲爱的 你一整天都没让她们吃饭吗
Honey, you haven't fed them all day?
她们就是怪兽 克莱尔
They're monsters, Claire --
奸猾狡诈又善于耍心机的怪兽
Deceitful, manipulative monsters --
我要让他们改邪归正
and they need to be broken.
他疯了
He's crazy!
你们知道吗 妈妈才是疯子
You know what?! Mom's the crazy one!
她开卡丁车时从我手上碾过去了
She ran over my hand.
我们当时玩儿的正高兴呢
We were having fun!
姑娘们 到厨房去
Girls, go to the kitchen.
找点东西吃
Get something to eat.
菲尔 亲爱的 这是行不通的
Phil, honey, this isn't working.
听我说 你不是当坏人的料
Listen to me,you are not a good bad cop,
而且我当好人也当得很糟糕
and I am a very bad good cop.
我们得各归其位 各司其职
We need things to go back to the way they were.
-对 -没错
- Yeah. - Yeah.
我都浑身发抖了
I feel really shaky.
我不喜欢当"你"
I don't like being you.
没人喜欢
Nobody does.
要出门吗
Going somewhere?
小卡 你起来了
Cam! You're up.
你没料到这点 对吧
Didn't count on that, did you?
你是要把莉莉放到你姐姐家去
Are you dropping lily off at your sister's,
还是她帮我去听演唱会啊
or is she taking my ticket?
好吧 首先 你怎么可能站在这儿
Okay, first of all, how are you standing?
你喝的那些咳嗽糖浆
You drank enough of that cough syrup
都足够放倒一只可怕的灰熊了
to put down a grizzly.
让我来告诉你什么是可怕吧
I'll tell you what's grisly.
你的行为
That is your behavior.
幸亏我是现在就发现了
Well, it's just a good thing I'm finding out now,
而不是我老病交加真正需要你的时候
instead of when I'm old and sick and really need you.
我最好现在就开始给家庭健康计划存钱
Better start saving for some sort of home-healthcare plan,
免得到时候我受伤的胯骨 或者持续性的肺炎
'cause I'd hate for my broken hip and subsequent pneumonia
妨碍到你的夜生活
to interfere with your evening plans.
小卡 不 你是对的
Okay, Cam, no, you're right.
你是对的
You're right.
我没什么好辩解的 我太糟糕了
I have no defense. I am terrible.
而且关键在于 我知道这样很无耻
And the thing is,I knew I was terrible,
可我还是去了
and I was going anyway.
或许我曾试图劝说自己
I think maybe I tried to justify it
咱们是不同类型的人
by saying we're two different people.
你更像是一个无私的奉献者
And you're more of a caregiver,
而我 则有其它的长处
and I have...other strengths.
而这才让我们那么登对 知道吗
And that's what makes us such a good couple, you know?
但是 不 不是的
But...No, no.
这只是我用来逃避的借口
It's a cop-out.
一直以来我都过分自私
And I've been very selfish,
我需要有所长进 而我也一定会的
and I need to do better, and I will.
我以莉莉的...
I swear on Lily's...
...尿布袋起誓
...diaper bag.
除了上去没别的选择了 对吧
Ah, no place to go but up, huh?
别那么看着我
Don't look at me like that.
家家有本难念的经
We all got problems.
这招没用的 宝贝儿
This ain't gonna work, sweetie.
你那楚楚可怜的眼神对我无效 来吧
That look ain't gonna work on me. Come on.
来吧 咱们走
Come on. Let's go.
我知道这很老套 不过我喜欢强势的男人
I know it's old-fashioned, but I like a strong man,
一个可以替我说"不"的男人
a man that can say no when I can't.
什么都别说
Not a word.
不过取而代之的 我有杰
But instead, I have Jay.
我很强势 不过你看看这张小脸
I'm strong. But look at this face.
也许我们是因为身边的人
Maybe we are the way we are
才成为现在的自己
because of the people we're with.
又或许 我们只是挑中了我们需要的人
Or maybe we just pick the people we need.
不管是怎样 当你们找到彼此
However it works, when you find each other,
就应该永远都不放手
you should never let go.
你想跟她独处一下吗
Do you two need some time alone?
我肯定是打了个盹
I must've dozed off.
对 你这个盹打得时间还挺长
Yeah, you were out for quite a while.
那你都干什么了
What have you been up to?
我就一直坐在这里 看着你
I've just been sitting here, watching you.
我要去睡觉了
Well I'm gonna go to bed.
好的
Okay.
谢谢你在家里陪着我
Thanks for staying home with me.
你懂的
Well, you know,
无论疾病或是健康嘛[婚誓内容]
in sickness and in health, right?
你的荧光棒还在闪呢 甜心
You're still blinking, sweetie.
完了 天啊
Oh, no. Oh, gosh.
那个 这个 真有意思
Well, this is-- this is funny.
我得告诉你件有意思的事
I'm gonna tell you the funny thing
关于为什么这个 这个会亮
about why this is, um-- this is on.